Payal Patel

UX/UI Designer

designer.payal2011@gmail.com G payal-patel-p5959p in

+1 (343)9872011 M

Enthusiastic UX/UI designer with 3+ years of design experience in User Interaction and Web design, as well as demonstrated an understanding of the pace and variety of corporate work. Seeking to obtain a UX/UI designer position to help the organization with strategic thinking and collaborative design at every stage of the game, from research to wireframes to visual design.

Research Interests

User Interface Design
User Experience Design
Wireframing
Interaction Design
Prototyping
Web Design
Graphics Design

Skills

Design

Adobe Photoshop • Adobe Illustrator • Adobe InDesign • After Effects • Adobe Premiere Pro • Sketch • Adobe XD • Adobe Lightroom • Adobe Spark • Canva

Research

Prototyping • Wireframing • User Journey • Product • Behavior • Storyboarding • Survey • Usability • Testing • Persona • Cognitive • Walkthrough

Programming

HTML5 • CSS3 • PHP • JavaScript • jQuery • Angular JS • Keynote • Vue JS • ASP.Net • SCSS • LESS • Bass CSS

Collaboration

Self-Starter • Detail • oriented • Flexible • Communicative • Responsive

Education Qualification

2018 - 2020

Algonquin College Canada

2010 - 2014

Gujarat Technological University India

Post-Graduation in Interactive Media Design

Digital graphics, Web Video Production, Applied Research Project, Motion Graphics, Server-Side Web Development, Content Management System

Bachelor of Engineering in Information & Technology

Object-Oriented Programming, Page Layout, Java, Php, ASP.Net, jQuery, SQL Database, Design tools, HTML, CSS

Work Experience

May 2019

Titus Inc. Canada

UX Design Intern

Worked on two significant projects: Data Classification for policy manager. Data Security for illuminate dashboard. Understand product specifications and their end-users. Designing wireframes and mockups. User testing. Solve complex UX problems. Worked with UI designer to implement designs. Communicate design ideas to developers.

2015 - 2018

LaNET Pvt. Ltd. India

Senior Web Designer

Worked on various graphic design projects. Tools for designing, infographics, email design, Logo design, Poster. Worked on Web design using Material design. Responsive tools, WordPress WooCommerce. Used jQuery for Web Animations like slider. CSS framework and third-party tools for various animations. Designed angular jQuery based custom components.

Conferences & Courses

AWS Public Sector Summit - Ottawa Amazon Web Services, Inc.

Design - Applying Design Principles Alison Courses

2014 - 2015

Idea to Working India

Junior Web Designer

Meeting with client and gathering requirements. Design and Develop web pages, also writing and editing web content. How to fix the error with optimum use of code. Basics of animations and transitions. Asp.Net framework to design web applications such as DotNetNuke.

Certificates

Introduction to HTML

Certificate / May 2018 - Present / License GREAUTN3GF58

Design - Applying Design Principles

Certificate / Jan 2018 - Present / License 206-10895623

JS Coding Challenges

MadLibs **Looping lyrics Functional fishing DOMinoes**

Using JavaScript Objects, Template literals Using Loops and Conditional statements Simple text-based game using functions DOM manipulation with flexbox to display 100

dominoes

Co-curricular Activities

AC Hub Community Project

Volunteer - Fall 2018

Welcoming new students, Responsibility to provide accurate information about college

Academic Project

Purple Eye – The Design User Experience Research, Personas, and User Scenario, Sitemap, Wireframing, Branding, Mood Studio User Interface Design boards

Explore Ottawa - The capital of Canada

Created a small business website using a child theme, Product post and Contact form feature

WordPress

iPhone - Apple

Drupal

Build in Drupal. Used a Sub theme to design and added features like product detail, SKU, blogs

CMS Monster

WordPress

CMS Monster is a comparison of 3 CMS giants (WordPress, Joomla, and Drupal). Used plugins and

modules.

Language Known

Awards and Honors

Dean's Honor's List 2019

English Hindi Gujarati

Online Projects

https://fritzandrose.com/ http://gates-ui.acid21.com/ https://www.modastylz.com/ http://www.avagtm.com/ https://www.myfundbucket.com/